TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Dennou Boukenki
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
녀석이 다이탈리온.
That is Ditalion.
Jadi ini yang namanya Ditalion.
안돼!
No!
Gawat!
액스 노바!
Axe Nova!
다이브 아웃해, 켄토! 다이브 아웃!
Dive Out, Kento! Dive Out!
Dive Out-lah, Kento! Cepat Dive Out!
싫어! 나 혼자 달아나는 건 싫어!
I won't! I won't run away and leave you behind!
Tidak! Aku tidak mau lari sendirian!
강제 다이브 아웃!
Forcing Dive Out!
Dive Out paksa!
다, 다이탈리온... 강해...
Ditalion... he's strong...
Ditalion... kuat sekali...
빛의 날개! 빅토리 글라디온
Wings of Light! Victory Gladion
Sayap Penuh Cahaya!
Victory Gladion
데리트로스 놈... 정말 다이탈리온 프로그램마저 이용해서 매지컬 백신을 없앤다는 것은.
That Deletloss... he even used Ditalion Program to get rid of Magical Vaccine.
Kurang ajar, Deletloss. Bisa-bisanya dia menggunakan program Ditalion untuk memusnahkan Magical Vaccine.
그 뿐인가. 글라디온 프로그램에 저만한 데미지를.
It's not only that. He even caused such damage to Gladion Program.
Bukan hanya itu saja. Dia bahkan menimbulkan kerusakan yang begitu parah pada program Gladion.
대체 어떻게 해야...
What should we do...
Bagaimana ini...
어떻게 해야 하는가... 이미 우리에겐 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨릴 방법은 없는가!
What can we do, then? Does this mean we lost our chance to win from Deletloss?
Apa yang harus kita lakukan? Apakah ini berarti kesempatan kita untuk menang dari Deletloss sudah hilang?
그렇게나 강해? 다이탈리온이라는 놈.
Is he really that strong? That Ditalion guy.
Hei, apa yang namanya Ditalion itu benar-benar sekuat itu, ya?
응, 강해. 지금까지 어떤 적보다도.
Yeah, he is. Stronger than any other enemies I've met before.
Iya. Sangat kuat. Jauh lebih kuat dari semua lawan selama ini.
공격을 피할 틈도 없었어.
We can't even evade from his attack.
Serangannya sama sekali tidak bisa dihindari.
글라디온의 복구가 끝나도 그 공격을 피할 수 없다면 우리에게 승산이란...
Even if Gladion recovers, without any way to evade that attack, we're never going to win.
Biarpun Gladion sudah selesai dipulihkan, kalau tidak bisa menghindar dari serangannya itu, kita tidak punya kesempatan menang.
젠장! 남은 건 다이탈리온 사이트 하나뿐인데!
Damn! Only Ditalion Site is remaining!
Sial! Padahal tinggal Ditalion Site saja!
조금만 더 하면 매지컬 게이트를! 카이토를 구해낼 수 있을 텐데!
A little bit more, then we'll be able to save Magical Gate and Kaito!
Tinggal sedikit lagi, Magical Gate... dan juga Kaito bisa kita rebut kembali!
켄토...
Kento...
글라디온!
Gladion!
드라그온?
Dragwon?
역시 켄토하고 함께 있었구나, 나오키. 빨리 매지컬 스테이션에 와라.
I'd expected you to be with Kento, Naoki. Come to Magical Station right now.
Sudah kuduga kau bersama Kento. Cepatlah datang ke Magical Station.
뭔 일이야?
Why?
Buat apa?
힘을 빌리고 싶다. 다이탈리온과 제대로 싸우기 위해서는 어떻게 해서든 찾아야만 한다.
I need your help. To fight against Ditalion evenly, whatever it takes, we need to find
Aku butuh bantuan. Untuk bisa bertarung dengan Ditalion, biar bagaimanapun juga, kita harus bisa menemukan
글라디온의 최강의 파트너를.
the strongest partner of Gladion.
teman Gladion yang paling kuat.
글라디온의 최강의 파트너?
Gladion's strongest partner?
Menemukan teman Gladion yang paling kuat?
자세한 내용은 나중에. 일단은 와 주려무나.
I'll explain the details later. Just come quickly for now.
Penjelasannya nanti saja. Yang penting sekarang segera datang.
-응, 알았어.
-그럼, 나도 가야지.                      -나도!
-Got it.
-Then, I'll go along with you.              -Me too!
-Baiklah.
-Kalau begitu, aku juga ikut.              -Aku juga!
켄토, 준비됐어뾰꼬!
Kento, we're ready-pyoko!
Kento, ayo berangkat-pyoko!
좋아.
Let's go.
Baiklah.
매지컬 게이트에 플러그 잇!
To Magical Gate, Plug It!
Menuju Magical Gate, Plug It!
와이버리온?
Wyverion?
그래. 와이버리온은 글라디온의 제 2의 프로그램. 또 하나의 글라디온이라고 불러도 괜찮은 웹나이트다.
That's right. Wyverion is the second program of Gladion.
Benar. Wyverion adalah program kedua Gladion. Webknight yang bisa dibilang sebagai Gladion lain.
The Webknight that deserves a title of another Gladion.
그런 웹나이트가 있었구나...
So there's a Webknight like that.
Jadi ada Webknight yang seperti itu, ya...
근데, 드라그온, 왜 와이버리온이 있으면 다이탈리온하고 제대로 싸울 수 있는데?
But, Dragwon, why would Gladion be able to fight against Ditalion evenly if he's with Wyverion?
Tapi, Dragwon, kenapa kalau ada Wyverion, kita jadi bisa bertarung seimbang dengan Ditalion?
와이버리온과 합체하면 글라디온은 최고 기동성을 보인다. 빅토리 글라디온이 된다.
By combining with Wyverion, Gladion will be able to change into his high speed mode, Victory Gladion.
Kalau bergabung dengannya, Gladion bisa berubah menjadi tipe kecepatan tinggi, Victory Gladion.
빅토리 글라디온!
Victory Gladion!
그렇구나! 그렇다면 다이탈리온에도 상대할 수 있겠네!
I see! He'll be able match Ditalion's power with that!
Jadi begitu, ya! Dengan begitu, kekuatan Ditalion bisa ditandingi!
근데 그 와이버리온은 지금 어디 있어?
But, where's that Wyverion guy now?
Tapi, Wyverion itu sekarang di mana?
그건...
That's...
Begini...
데리트로스가 매지컬 게이트를 침략할 때 와이버리온은 놈에게 지배받지 않고 동면 중이었다.
When Deletloss invaded Magical Gate, he sent himself to hibernate so he wouldn't be controlled.
Saat Magical Gate direbut Deletloss, agar tidak sampai dikuasainya, Wyverion menidurkan dirinya sendiri.
어쩌면 지금도 동면 중일 지 모르지만, 매지컬 게이트 안에서 떠돌고 있다는 것만은 확실해.
He must be somewhere in Magical Gate and is still hibernating.
Pasti dia sekarang ada di suatu tempat di Magical Gate dalam keadaan masih tertidur.
다만 정확한 위치는 알 수 없어.
But his exact location is unknown.
Tapi, lokasi tempatnya tidak diketahui.
-그런...
-아니야. 어쩌면 알 수도 있어뾰꼬.
-No way...
-No. Maybe we can figure it out-pyoko.
-Ya ampun...
-Mungkin kita bisa menemukannya-pyoko.
모두의 활약 덕분에 매지컬 게이트도 다이탈리온 사이트 빼고 전부 해방됐어뾰꼬.
Thanks to everyone's effort, Magical Gate has been freed except for Ditalion Site-pyoko.
Berkat usaha Kento dan kalian semua, Magical Gate kecuali Ditalion Site bisa dibebaskan-pyoko.
그러니까 지금은 남은 곳에서 찾아보기만 하면 될 거야뾰꼬.
So we will only have to search in the remaining area-pyoko.
Dengan begitu, aku tinggal mencari di area yang tersisa-pyoko.
그렇구나! 카론, 지금 바로 찾아 줘!
Awesome! Karon, please look for him right now!
Begitu, ya! Karon, tolong cepat cari dia, ya!
알았어뾰꼬!
Got it-pyoko!
Baik-pyoko!
저건?
What's that?
Apa itu?
찾았어뾰꼬! 와이버리온이야뾰꼬!
I found him-pyoko! It's Wyverion!
Ketemu! Itu Wyverion-pyoko!
계산대로라면 한 시간 후에 쥬라식 에이리어를 지나갈 거에용!
According to the calculations, he'll pass Jurassic Area in an hour-pyoko!
Menurut perhitungan, dia akan melewati Jurassic Area dalam waktu sejam lagi-pyoko!
쥬라식 에이리어라고?
Jurassic Area?
왜, 켄토.
What's the matter, Kento?
Memangnya kenapa, Kento?
쥬라식 에이리어는... 카이토가 행방불명이 된 에이리어야.
Jurassic Area is... the place where Kaito disappeared.
Jurassic Area... adalah area dimana Kaito menghilang.
그랬구나...
I didn't knew...
Jadi begitu, ya...
-하자, 나오키.
-응?
Let's do it, Naoki.
Ayo kita lakukan, Naoki.
와이버리온을 붙잡자.
Let's catch Wyverion.
Ayo kita tangkap Wyverion.
-그래!
-그럼 나도!
-Okay!
-Great! Me too then!
-Iya!
-Bagus! Aku juga!
아, 아직 글라디온이...
Ah, but Gladion is not yet...
Ah, tapi Gladion masih belum...
글라디온...
Gladion...
그렇다면 내가 함께 가 줄게, 켄토!
If that's the case, I'll take you there instead, Kento!
Kalau begitu, aku akan membawamu ke sana, Kento!
재규어온!
Jaguaron!
그러니까, 와이버리온을 잡기 위해서는 속도라면 지지 않는 내가 제격이지!
If we want to catch Wyverion, it's time for me to be in action with my speed!
Kalau mau menangkap Wyverion, saatnya bagiku yang berkecepatan tinggi untuk beraksi!
고마워, 재규어온!
Thank you, Jaguaron!
Terima kasih, ya, Jaguaron!
그럼, 쥬라식 에이리어에서 보자고.
Then, let's meet in Jurassic Area.
Kalau begitu, kita bertemu di Jurassic Area.
좋아! 가자, 켄토!
Great! Now let's go, Kento!
Baik! Ayo kita berangkat, Kento!
쥬라식 에이리어는 다이탈리온 사이트 안이야! 둘 다 조심해!
Jurassic Area is in Ditalion Site! Be careful, you two!
Jurassic Area terletak di Ditalion Site! Kalian berdua harus berhati-hati, ya!
알고 있어, 아오이!
We already know that, Aoi!
Iya, aku tahu, Aoi!
이게 쥬라식 에이리어...
This is Jurassic Area...?
Jurassic Area jadi begini...
참혹하네...
Such a scary place.
Sungguh mengerikan.
어, 드라그온은? 아직 안 왔어?
Where's Dragwon? Is he here yet?
Mana Dragwon? Apa dia belum datang?
그럼 난 드라그온을 찾아 볼게!
Alright, then I'll go find Dragwon!
Baiklah, aku akan mencari Dragwon!
켄토, 왜 그래?
Kento, what's wrong?
Kento, ada apa?
이게 그 때의!
This is the escape gate
Ini adalah pintu darurat
탈출 게이트...
of that time...
yang waktu itu...
서둘러!
Run away!
Ayo cepat!
카이토!
Kaito!
형!
Kento!
Kakak!
카이토! 카이토!
Kaito! Kaito!
젠장! 데리트로스 놈! 안됄! 망할! 카이토를! 카이토를 돌려줘!
Damned that Deletloss! Go to hell! Give my Kaito back! Give him back!
Keterlaluan! Kurang ajar! Deletloss sial! Kembalikan Kaito! Kembalikan!
켄토!
Kento!
빨리 달아나!
Hurry up and run away!
Ayo cepat lari!
어, 어떻게 된 거야, 켄토! 쥬라식 에이리어에 공룡이 대체 왜 살아 있냐고!
Explain this, Kento! The dinosaurs in Jurassic Area aren't supposed to chase people!
Kenapa bisa begini, Kento?! Seharusnya dinosaurus di Jurassic Area tidak mengejar orang!
몰라! 그딴 거!
Like hell I'd know that!
Hah?! Mana kutahu!
야, 켄토, 뭐라도 해 봐!
Hey, Kento, what should we do?!
Kento, bagaimana ini?!
걱정 마, 나오키! 이건 그냥 프로그램일 뿐이잖아. 영상의 문제인걸.
Don't worry, Naoki! This is nothing more than a program. Just like 3D projection.
Tidak perlu takut, Naoki! Itu, kan, cuma program. Hanya seperti bayangan 3 dimensi saja.
그랬지! 하하! 그렇구나! 여기가 다이탈리온 사이트라고 해봤자,
Oh, that's true! I almost forgot! Even if this is Ditalion Site,
Benar juga! Aku sampai lupa! Biarpun ini adalah Ditalion Site,
매지컬 게이트에 다를 건 없네. 얘 뭐하냐? 겁주려는 거냐?
nothing has changed in Magical Gate! What's this guy doing? Trying to scare us?
tapi, Magical Gate tetap tidak berubah, ya! Makhluk seperti ini saja, tidak menakutkan!
이게 뭐야, 방금.
What was that just now...
Yang tadi itu apa...
데리트로스 때문에 프로그램들이 이상해졌나봐.
I guess the programs became weird because of Deletloss.
Pasti gara-gara ulah Deletloss, programnya jadi aneh.
-그럼...
-설마...
-That's...
-Don't tell me...
-Suara itu...
-Jangan-jangan...
드라그온!
Dragwon!
늦어서 미안하군. 괜찮니, 나오키?
Sorry I'm late. Are you all right, Naoki?
Maaf aku terlambat. Kau tidak apa-apa?
응, 고마워!
Yeah, thanks!
Iya, terima kasih!
저, 저건...
Look at that...
Apa itu?
왔군, 와이버리온.
Wyverion has arrived.
Wyverion sudah tiba.
저게 와이버리온.
That's Wyverion?
Jadi itu, Wyverion?
Brought to you by Subdiver
웹다이브!
Webdive!
드라그온!
Dragwon!
잘 해 줘, 나오키, 드라그온!
Please stop him, Naoki, Dragwon!
Tolong, ya, Naoki, Dragwon!
가자! 드라그온!
Let's do it, Dragwon!
Ayo, Dragwon!
힘내! 나오키! 드라그온!
Do your best, both of you!
Naoki, Dragwon, berjuanglah!
좋아! 나오키! 드라그온!
Great job, Naoki, Dragwon!
Wah, kalian berhasil!
저게!
That's!
Itu!
와이버리온!
Wyverion!
용서 못 해. 절대 용서 못 해!
I will not forgive. I can never forgive!
Tidak bisa diampuni. Tidak bisa diampuni!
와이버리온이 눈을 떴어.
Wyverion has awaken.
Sepertinya Wyverion sudah sadar.
잠깐, 뭔가 모습이 이상해.
Wait a moment, something's not right about him.
Tunggu dulu. Dia kelihatannya aneh.
용서 못 해. 절대 용서 못 해!
I will not forgive. I can never forgive!
Tidak bisa diampuni. Tidak bisa diampuni!
나오키! 드라그온!
Naoki! Dragwon!
대체 뭐가 어떻게 된 거야! 설마
와이버리온도 데리트로스에게?!
What the heck is going on!? Don't tell me he's controlled by Deletloss too!
Ada apa dengan dia?! Jangan-jangan Wyverion juga dikendalikan Deletloss!
아냐, 아니야. 아직 와이버리온은 완전히 깨어나지 않은 것 같다.
No, he's not. Wyverion seems to be not fully waken up yet.
Tidak, bukan begitu. Sepertinya Wyverion belum sepenuhnya sadar.
동료인지 적인지 구별을 할 수 없는 것 같군. 우릴 적으로 생각하는 것 같은데.
He cannot identify if we are his enemies or friends yet, but I think he feels that we're his enemy.
Dia belum bisa membedakan kawan atau lawan. Sepertinya dia mengira kita adalah musuhnya.
저런...
That's too bad...
Ya ampun...
용서할 수 없다! 절대!
You will not be forgiven! Never!
Tidak bisa diampuni. Tidak bisa diampuni!
뿌리칠 수가 없군. 이대로라면 잡히겠어!
There's no end to this. At this rate we'll be beaten up!
Tidak ada habisnya. Kalau begini terus kita bisa hancur!
-어쩔 거야, 드라그온!
-이렇게 된 바, 무리해서라도 일단 치고 보는 수밖에 없어!
-What should we do, Dragwon?!
-We have no other choice than to hit him in this state!
-Bagaimana ini, Dragwon?!
-Terpaksa, kita harus bertarung dan memaksa dia berhenti!
-무리하겠다니?
-걱정 마! 적당히 할 테니까!
-Hit him!?
-Don't worry! It's just to wake him up!
-Harus bertarung?!
-Jangan khawatir! Ini untuk menyadarkannya!
적당하긴 뭐가 적당해!?
But even so!
Tapi, kan!
용서 못 해!
I will not forgive!
Tidak bisa diampuni!
블랙 홀 캐논!
Black Hole Cannon!
어, 와이버리온!
Wyverion!
어때, 좀 깼어? 잠투정은 그만 부려.
How's that? You've awaken now, right? Geez, you're so hard to be woken up.
Bagaimana? Kau sudah sadar, kan? Dasar, bangun tidur langsung ngamuk.
뭐야?! 없어졌어?! 말도 안 돼...
What the?! He disappeared? No way...
D-dia hilang?! Mustahil!
용서 못 해!
No forgivance!
Tidak bisa diampuni!
내 블랙 홀 캐논을 피하다니 엄청난 속도야!
To evade my Black Hole Cannon, that's some speed!
Black Hole Cannon-ku bisa dihindarinya! Kecepatan macam apa itu?!
속도라면 나에게 맡겨!
I won't lose when it comes to speed!
Dalam hal kecepatan, aku tidak akan kalah!
이번엔 내가 상대해 주마, 와이버리온!
This time I'll be your match, Wyverion!
Sekarang akulah lawanmu, Wyverion!
기다려!
Stop right there!
Berhenti kau!
빠르잖아! 내 최고 속력으로도 못 잡는다니,
He's fast! I can't catch him with my full speed!
Cepat sekali! Kecepatan penuhku tidak sanggup mengimbanginya!
드라그온! 재규어온!
Dragwon! Jaguaron!
용서 못 해! 용서할 것 같냐!
Unforgivable! I won't forgive!
Tidak bisa diampuni! Tidak bisa diampuni!
글라디온!
Gladion!
아슬아슬하게나마 만나서 다행이야, 켄토! 미안하다. 날 위해 무리하다니.
I'm glad I made it there. Kento, I'm sorry. I've made you force yourself just for my sake.
Untunglah tidak terlambat. Kento, maaf ya. Kau sudah memaksakan diri demi aku.
고맙다.
Thank you.
Terima kasih banyak.
걱정 마, 글라디온!
Don't mind it, Gladion!
Tidak perlu dipikirkan, Gladion!
자, 켄토. 웹다이브해라! 와이버리온을 잡으러 가자!
Now, Kento, Webdive! Let's go catch Wyverion!
Nah, Kento, cepat Webdive! Kita tangkap Wyverion!
좋아!
Alright!
Baiklah!
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
웹체인지! 글라디온, 파이터 모드!
Webchange! Gladion, Fighter Mode!
-글라디온!
-오지 마, 드라그온, 재규어온!
-Gladion!
-Stay put, both of you!
-Jangan mendekat, Dragwon, Jaguaron!
여기는 나에게 맡겨 줘!
Leave this to me!
Kali ini serahkan saja padaku!
어쩔 생각이야, 글라디온?
What are you going to do, Gladion?
Apa yang akan kau lakukan, Gladion?
-강제합체한다!
-강제합체?
-Forced fusion!
-Forced fusion?
-Aku akan lakukan gabungan secara paksa!
-Bergabung secara paksa?
나하고 와이버리온은 일심동체. 그러니까 합체하면 눈을 뜰 거야!
Wyverion and I are one. Thus he will definitely wake up if we combine!
Aku dan Wyverion adalah satu. Karena itu, kalau kami bergabung, pasti dia akan tersadar!
그렇구나. 알았어.
I see. Got it.
Begitu, ya. Aku mengerti.
용서 못 해! 용서할 것 같나!
I will never forgive you! Like hell I will!
Tidak bisa diampuni! Tidak bisa diampuni!
왜 그래, 와이버리온.
What's irritating you, Wyverion?
Wyverion, apa yang terjadi denganmu?
좋아. 강제합체. 빅토리 모드!
Now let's do the forced fusion. Victory Mode!
Nah, lakukan gabungan paksa, Victory Mode!
그래.
Do it.
Baiklah.
글라디온, 빅토리 모드!
Gladion, Victory Mode!
뭐가 문제야, 글라디온!
What's the problem, Gladion?!
Apa yang terjadi, Gladion?!
와이버리온의 데이터가 너무 강해서 흘러 넘쳐 오고 있어! 제어 불가!
Wyverion's data is overflowing into me! I cannot take control of him!
Data Wyverion mengalir masuk dengan deras! Aku tidak bisa mengendalikannya!
용서할 수 없다! 절대!
You will never be forgived! Never!
Tidak bisa diampuni! Tidak bisa diampuni!
와이버리온!
Wyverion!
여긴...
Here is...
Dimana ini?
용서 못 해. 용서 못 해! 잘도 아이들을!
I cannot forgive. I will not forgive! How dare you did that to the children!
Tidak bisa diampuni! Tidak bisa diampuni! Beraninya kau lakukan ini pada anak-anak!
와이버리온!
Wyverion!
여긴,
This place is...
Ini...
그렇구나, 이게 기억. 와이버리온의 기억이구나. 그럼 여긴 와이버리온 안?
I see. So this is his memory-- Wyverion's memory. It means I'm inside him?
Begitu, ya? Ini adalah memori Wyverion. Berarti, aku di dalam Wyverion?
구하지 못했다.
I failed.
Gagal.
아이들을 구하지 못했다.
I failed to rescue the children.
Aku tidak bisa menyelamatkan anak-anak.
매지컬 게이트를 지키는 웹나이트조차 아니였다.
I'm a Webknght who's tasked to protect Magical Gate.
Padahal aku adalah Webknight yang bertugas menjaga Magical Gate.
누구 하나 구하지 못했다!
Yet I failed to rescue even a single child!
Tapi tidak seorangpun yang bisa kuselamatkan!
-와이버리온.
-나는, 나는!
-Wyverion.
-I am... I am...!
-Aku... aku...!
아냐, 아니야! 어쩔 수 없었어! 방법 하나 없었어!
No, that's not it! It can't be helped! There's nothing you can do about it!
Tidak, bukan begitu! Ini bukan kesalahanmu! Tidak ada yang bisa kau lakukan!
넌 누구냐.
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
나는 켄토. 유우키 켄토. 글라디온의 웹다이버야.
I am Kento, Yuuki Kento. Gladion's Webdiver.
Aku ini Kento. Yuuki Kento. Aku Webdiver Gladion.
글라디온?
Gladion?
부탁이야, 와이버리온. 데리트로스에게서 매지컬 게이트를 되찾고 싶으면 나에게, 글라디온에게 힘을 빌려 줘!
Please, Wyverion! Lend us your power to take back Magical Gate from Deletloss' hand!
Aku mohon, Wyverion. Pinjamkanlah kekuatanmu padaku, pada Gladion, untuk membebaskan Magical Gate dari cengkraman Deletloss!
나는 아이들을 구해내지 못했다. 웹나이트로서 실격이다!
I failed to save the children. I am a failure as a Webknight!
Aku tidak bisa menyelamatkan anak-anak. Aku tidak pantas menjadi Webknight.
그럼 그걸로 포기해 버린다면 끝이잖아!
Even so, if you give up just like that, that's just the end for you!
Meskipun begitu, kalau kau menyerah, berarti kau sudah berakhir!
포기해도 좋아? 정말 그래도 돼?
더 이상 아이들을 구할 생각은 없어?
Are you okay with giving up like that? Are you really sure? Don't you want to save those children?!
Apa kau lebih suka begini?! Apa kau menyerah begitu saja?! Apa kau tidak ingin menyelamatkan anak-anak?!
나는,
I...
Aku...
나는,
I...
Aku...
나는 포기하지 않아! 모두에게 힘을 빌린다면 데리트로스를 쓰러뜨릴 수 있을 거야!
I won't give up! If everyone's power is combined, Deletloss can be defeated!
Aku tidak akan menyerah! Kalau semuanya menyatukan kekuatan, Deletloss pasti bisa dikalahkan!
네가 구하지 못한 아이들도 꼭 구해낼 수 있을 거야!
And we can save those children you failed to save as well!
Anak-anak yang gagal kau tolong pasti bisa diselamatkan!
정말이라면...
Is that true?
Benarkah itu?
응. 난 카이토를, 모두를 구하고 싶어!
Yes. I want to save Kaito. I want to save everyone!
Iya. Aku ingin menolong Kaito, dan juga yang lainnya!
구하지 않으면 안 돼! 그 생각만은 같지, 와이버리온!
We must save them! You must be feeling the same thing, right, Wyverion?
Aku tidak boleh sampai gagal! Lagipula, perasaan kita sama, kan, Wyverion?
나는... 나도! 나도 구하고 싶어! 아이들을!
I... Me too! I want to save those children!
Aku... Aku juga! Aku juga ingin menolong anak-anak itu!
-와이버리온!
-같이 싸우자, 유우키 켄토!
-Wyverion!
-Let's fight together, Yuuki Kento!
-Ayo kita bertarung bersama, Yuuki Kento!
데리트로스에게 빼앗긴 모든 걸 되찾기 위해!
To take back everything that Deletloss has stolen!
Untuk merebut kembali semua yang telah diambil Deletloss!
와이버리온!
Wyverion!
미안했다, 글라디온. 이젠 괜찮다.
I'm sorry, Gladion, but everything's all right now.
Maafkan aku, Gladion. Sekarang aku sudah kembali normal.
그래, 그렇다면 나에게 힘을 빌려 줘!
악을 근절시킬 승리의 힘을!
Good, then lend me your power!
The power of victory that will exterminate evil!
Bagus, kalau begitu, pinjamkan kekuataku padamu! Kekuatan kemenangan untuk menghancurkan kejahatan!
물론!
Of course!
Ya!
글라디온, 빅토리 모드!
Gladion, Victory Mode!
웹체인지! 와이버리온, 윙 모드!
Webchange! Wyverion, Wing Mode!
빅토리 글라디온!
Victory Gladion!
저게 빅토리 글라디온!
So that's Victory Gladion!
Jadi itu Victory Gladion?
글라디온. 네놈 따위가 어떻게든 강해졌다 해도
Gladion, even if you've powered up,
Gladion, biarpun kekuatanmu bertambah,
이 몸을 쓰러뜨릴 수 있겠나?
will you be able to take me down?
kau tidak akan bisa mengalahkan Deletloss ini!
대단해.
What a strength.
Wah, ini hebat.
이 속도와 힘... 이것이 빅토리 글라디온의 힘.
This speed and power... This is the power of Victory Gladion.
Kecepatan dan kekuatan yang dashyat! Inikah kemampuan Victory Gladion?
글라디온.
Gladion.
데리트로스!
Deletloss!
빅토리 참!
Victory Slash!
기다려라, 데리트로스! 넌 기필코 내가 쓰러뜨린다!
Just you wait, Deletloss! I will definitely defeat you!
Tunggu saja, Deletloss! Aku pasti akan menghancurkan dirimu!
빅토리 글라디온이라. 건방진 놈.
Victory Gladion. What an impertinent guy.
Victory Gladion. Kelihatannya hebat juga.
그래봤자, 잊으면 안 된다. 너희들은 이 몸을 제거할 수도 이길 수도 없다.
But you all seem to have forgotten that there's no way you can defeat me.
Tapi sepertinya kalian sudah lupa, kalau kalian tidak mungkin bisa mengalahkanku.
왜냐면 말이지,
That's because...
Kalian tahu kenapa?
Screenplay
Kubota Masashi
Storyboarding
Ishiyama Takaaki
Staging
Katou Shigeru
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Gladion
Arisugawa Aoi
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Kobayashi Yumiko
Sugita Tomokazu
Kikuchi Shiho
Karon
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Arisugawa Professor
Tobita Nobuo
Voice Actor
Jaguaron
Kawashima Tokuyoshi
Wyverion
Konishi Katsuyuki
Dragwon
Kawada Shinji
Deletloss
Fumihiko Tachiki
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Insert Song
Dear Friend, To the Far Side of Dream
: Gladion's Theme
Lyrics
Sugita Tomokazu
Composer
Daimon Kazuya
Arranger
Singer
(Sugita Tomokazu)
Gladion
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Production
Thank you for watching!
다음 이야기 미리보기
Preview for Next Episode
Episode Selanjutnya
다이버랜드에 설치된 사악한 기운의 폭탄.
The Evil Aura Bomb is installed over Diverland.
Terdapat bom aura jahat yang diletakkan di Diverland.
뭐라고? 12시 정각에 다이버랜드가 소멸한다고?
What? Diverland will disappear right at 12'o clock?
Apa? Diverland akan hancur saat jam 12 malam?
가자, 글라디온.
Let's hurry, Gladion.
Kita harus bergegas, Gladion!
한시라도 빨리 다이탈리온을 쓰러뜨리자!
We need to defeat Ditalion as soon as possible!
Kita harus mengalahkan Ditalion secepatnya!
다이탈리온과의 결전이 지금 시작해.
The final battle against Ditalion begins now.
Pertempuran terakhir melawan Ditalion akhirnya dimulai.
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !